"For loops" are an example of definite iteration,
meaning that the loop's body is run a predefined number of times.
A "for loop" over a list,
executes the body once for each element in the list.
A "for loop" using the range function will
execute the number of times specified by the range function.
This differs from indefinite iteration,
which is when a loop repeats an unknown number of
times and ends when some condition is met.
Consider this "while loop" that simulates a blackjack dealer by drawing cards from
a deck list into a hand list stopping when
the value of the cards in the hand is 17 or more.
This example features a new function "sum" and a new list method "pop".
Sum is pretty intuitive,
it returns the sum of the elements in a list.
Pop is the inverse of the append method,
it removes the last element from a list and returns it.
You can read more about this in the official documentation.
In this line, we are computing the sum of
the list hand and checking if that is less than or equal to 17.
In this line, we're popping the last element
from card deck and appending that to the hand list.
Let's talk about how this "while loop" works.
The while keyword indicates that this is a while loop.
Next is the condition.
In this example, sum hand is less than or equal to 17.
If this condition is true,
the loop's body will be executed.
Each time the loop's body runs,
the condition is evaluated again.
This process of checking the condition and then running
the loop repeats until the expression becomes false.
The indented body of the loop should modify at least one variable in the test expression.
If the value of the test expression never changes,
the result is an infinite loop.
In this example, the loop's body appends numbers to the hand lists,
which increases the value of sum hand.
Eventually, the value of sum hand becomes large enough that the condition becomes false.